<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>grumble on Fang's Blog</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/categories/grumble/</link><description>Recent content in grumble on Fang's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 10:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peromage.github.io/categories/grumble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving From Vim to Emacs</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/moving-from-vim-to-emacs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/moving-from-vim-to-emacs/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube has been pushing me a lot Emacs related contents. This is weird since mostly I watch Vim videos only. But probably this is also a great opportunity to try Emacs again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have tried Emacs half year ago. I looked a lot Elisp programming fundamentals and tried a few Emacs configurations from others including Doom Emacs. However, it didn&amp;rsquo;t last long since I found that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough time to configure this Emacs setup as good as the &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/peromage/rice.vim" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Vim setup&lt;/a> that I was using. Also using other&amp;rsquo;s configurations makes things complicated for me. They have too many packages included and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After watching a bunch of Emacs videos I decided to pick it up this time, with vanilla Emacs starting from scratch. The reason why I make my mind this time is because I found Emacs can perfectly and elegantly solve some problems that pain my ass:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>More convenient package management.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>High quality packages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easier file management in shell environment within the editor (Dired)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No third party dependencies like Node.js and Python. The two major plugs that I&amp;rsquo;m using in Vim are &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/neoclide/coc.nvim" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Coc&lt;/a> and &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/Yggdroot/LeaderF" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Leaderf&lt;/a>. They require Node.js and Python to work. Since Elisp is power enough, Emacs can handle this easily by itself.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Server-client architecture. I can even replace Tmux with Emacs now. NeoVim has the similar concept but it cannot match what Emacs has.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphical interface in X mode. This makes Emacs be able to display rich contents.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Org mode. It looks great to organize todo list and take notes without switching to other applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evil mode. No need to worry about missing Vim&amp;rsquo;s features.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Magit. Looks way better and nicer than fugitive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Elisp. Elisp is fun 😉.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The migration is going slowly. Right now my main setup is still Vim + Tmux. There is a little curve learning from vanilla edition of Emacs, but It&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal compared with the first time when I started learning Vim 🙂.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, dont&amp;rsquo;t give me wrong. Vim and Emacs both are great text editor. For me, Vim is more like a spirit, a concept. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve learned its high-efficiency key maps, you can use it everywhere. Even though I switch to Emacs I still use Vim mode together with Emacs&amp;rsquo; powerful extendability. Why not?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>