<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on undefined behavior</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on undefined behavior</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 17:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peromage.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>File-based Blog Management with ox-hugo</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/file-based-blog-management-with-ox-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/file-based-blog-management-with-ox-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I previously wrote a &lt;a href="https://peromage.github.io/p/use-org-mode-to-manage-my-blog/">post&lt;/a> about managing blog posts with ox-hugo in org mode. I used to follow the recommendation to keep posts under org subtrees. As posts grew, I found that the opening speed is quite slow even I didn&amp;rsquo;t have many pictures inserted. Although managing the entire site within one file does have some convenience, the slowness is something I can&amp;rsquo;t bear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also I feel it a little awkward when I use the subtree style management. I always worried about if the format was correct like how many empty lines between posts or if something was accidentally changed outside of the post that I was editing. And in order to maintain the subtree structure, the actual posts have to be indented (nested), which is not what I like. There are solutions for this nested editing. I used to use &lt;code>org-narrow-to-subtree&lt;/code> when I was editing the post and use &lt;code>widen&lt;/code> to switch the view back. But still, I always worried about the format (please forgive OCD patient).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Org Mode to Manage My Blog</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/use-org-mode-to-manage-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/use-org-mode-to-manage-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Emacs since last year but until recent I started using &lt;code>org-mode&lt;/code> seriously. After spending a couple of days reading and watching all kinds of org tutorial as well as using it for documentation, I realized that people who invented this must geniuses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Org document seems similar with Markdown: they are text markup format. However, Org provides far more capabilities to store metadata and greater editing experience together with Emacs&amp;rsquo; &lt;code>org-mode&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>