<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Multi_boot on undefined behavior</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/tags/multi_boot/</link><description>Recent content in Multi_boot on undefined behavior</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 19:07:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peromage.github.io/tags/multi_boot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Archive] Multiboot USB</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/archive-multiboot-usb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/archive-multiboot-usb/</guid><description>Boot from any ISO file Hybrid UEFI GPT + BIOS MBR/GPT boot Preparation Create 3 partitions on a removable USB stick. A BIOS boot partition (gdisk type code EF02, or GUID 21686148-6449-6E6F-744E-656564454649) with no filesystem. This partition can be put in any place on the disk but it is recommended to put it at the begginning from sector 34 to 2047. At minimal 1 MiB. An EFI System partition (gdisk</description></item><item><title>Windows Rescure Quick Reference</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</guid><description>Though I&amp;rsquo;ve written posts about dual-booting Windows and Linux and multi-booting a USB drive, I have to go back and dig useful information out each time when I forget something.
After breaking my dual-boot setup once again (forgot to backup boot partition), I decided to create this post for a quick reference.
This reference assumes system is boot from UEFI and Windows is installed on a dedicated partition.
Setup A USB With System Images Forget the previous multi-boot USB post.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist's Multi-boot USB Drive</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/minimalists-multi-boot-usb-drive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/minimalists-multi-boot-usb-drive/</guid><description>Story Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve realized a fact that I always have needs to keep a multi-boot USB in my pocket for either Linux or Windows installation. There are a lot tools out there already but I don&amp;rsquo;t really like them. At least, I mean, they are too flashy to me. A beautiful boot menu seems not to be attractive. What I need is just a simple and practical maybe a little ugly boot device.</description></item></channel></rss>