<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on undefined behavior</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on undefined behavior</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peromage.github.io/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows Rescure Quick Reference</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</guid><description>Though I&amp;rsquo;ve written posts about dual-booting Windows and Linux and multi-booting a USB drive, I have to go back and dig useful information out each time when I forget something.
After breaking my dual-boot setup once again (forgot to backup boot partition), I decided to create this post for a quick reference.
This reference assumes system is boot from UEFI and Windows is installed on a dedicated partition.
Setup A USB With System Images Forget the previous multi-boot USB post.</description></item><item><title>My Common Windows VM Setup</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/my-common-windows-vm-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/my-common-windows-vm-setup/</guid><description>Before Starting This post mainly discusses VM setup for Windows since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Windows as a secondary OS for apps or games that cannot run on Linux.
This post discusses setup on Arch Linux.
This post assumes the CPU and motherboard support VT-d and IOMMU features. Detailed prerequisites can be found on this page.
Install Hypervisor Follow Arch wiki to install and setup:
QEMU Libvirt Virt-Manager OVMF Install Windows VM Before Installation Download the latest Windows 10 ISO from Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Dual-booting Windows VHD and Native Linux on a BIOS+GPT PC</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/dual-booting-windows-vhd-and-native-linux-on-a-bios-gpt-pc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/dual-booting-windows-vhd-and-native-linux-on-a-bios-gpt-pc/</guid><description>Background Previously I wrote a post for this dual-boot scenario. It is a little outdated. In the past year I mostly worked in the Linux environment on my old laptop, so the Windows seems not to be a necessity which occupies a dedicated partition. However, sometimes it is still needed. That is why I started thinking to improve this setup even further. Starting from Windows 7, Windows supports boots from</description></item><item><title>Windows+Linux双系统引导手记</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-linux%E5%8F%8C%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%BC%95%E5%AF%BC%E6%89%8B%E8%AE%B0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 19:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-linux%E5%8F%8C%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%BC%95%E5%AF%BC%E6%89%8B%E8%AE%B0/</guid><description>0x00 情况简述 由于开发需要 Linux 环境，所以将老的那台笔记本改造成了双系统。 这台电脑的基本情况是这样的，64GB 固态硬盘 + 720GB 机械硬盘（实际可用空间有折</description></item></channel></rss>