<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on (->> truth seek (desire))</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on (->> truth seek (desire))</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peromage.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows Rescure Quick Reference</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-rescure-quick-reference/</guid><description>Though I&amp;rsquo;ve written posts about dual-booting Windows and Linux and multi-booting a USB drive, I have to go back and dig useful information out each time when I forget something.
After breaking my dual-boot setup once again (forgot to backup boot partition), I decided to create this post for a quick reference.
This reference assumes system is boot from UEFI and Windows is installed on a dedicated partition.
Setup A USB With System Images Forget the previous multi-boot USB post.</description></item><item><title>VNC Quick Guide</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/vnc-quick-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/vnc-quick-guide/</guid><description>I found that every time when I try to setup VNC for remote access I always have troubles configuring it. I believe this is due to some conceptions which can be easily confusing. So this post serves both notes and reminder for myself.
Choose a VNC Server Generally I use TigerVNC. It&amp;rsquo;s a fork of TightVNC and the performance is pretty good. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to configure. However, when it comes to installation there are two types of servers: standalone and scraping.</description></item><item><title>Setup A Gaming VM</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/setup-a-gaming-vm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/setup-a-gaming-vm/</guid><description>Before starting First thing first. I&amp;rsquo;ve been rarely using Windows over years except for working and gaming. Linux community grows fast and there are a lot alternatives available. On the contrary, Windows gets crapy every year (Office 365 is still good IMO) so there is no reason to run this huge spyware all the time.
Modern PCs are strong enough to run a VM. Besides most of PCs have both integrated and descret graphic cards.</description></item><item><title>Fix Metadata in Google Photo Takeout</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/fix-metadata-in-google-photo-takeout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/fix-metadata-in-google-photo-takeout/</guid><description>Google Photo sucks.
Troubles When exporting photos from Google Photo, a bunch of JSON files come with your photos. Those JSON files contain metadata which is supposed to be stored with your photo files. If you simple import those photo files into another photo manager you will most likely not get a chronological view. Obviously, Google does on purpose so that you will not leave it easily. However, there is a workaround that is able to merge those metadata into your photos.</description></item><item><title>Shadowsocks Quick Setup</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/shadowsocks-quick-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/shadowsocks-quick-setup/</guid><description>This note is written for my personal convenience.
Server Setup Installation Use system package manager to install shadowsocks-libev. In this case, for Arch Linux it is pacman.
There is also a Python package which can be installed by pip but it seems not to be maintained for a long time.
$ sudo pacman -S shadowsocks-libev Shadowsocks Server Configuration Config file is located at /etc/shadowsocks/myserver.json. On FreeBSD it is /usr/local/etc/shadowsocks/myserver.json
The file name can vary.</description></item><item><title>SSH Over GPG Agent</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/ssh-over-gpg-agent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/ssh-over-gpg-agent/</guid><description>This is a quick note of gpg-agent setup for SSH.
Quick Setup Import your GPG authentication key. Enable SSH support for gpg-agent. $ echo enable-ssh-support &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $HOME/.gnupg/gpg-agent.conf Get the authentication keygrip. $ gpg -k --with-keygrip Add the authentication key to the keychain (replace KEYGRIP with the value obtained from the previous step) $ echo KEYGRIP &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $HOME/.gnupg/sshcontrol Add the following init code to .bashrc unset SSH_AGENT_PID export SSH_AUTH_SOCK=&amp;#34;$(gpgconf --list-dirs agent-ssh-socket)&amp;#34; export GPG_TTY=&amp;#34;$(tty)&amp;#34; gpg-connect-agent updatestartuptty /bye &amp;gt; /dev/null Kill any running ssh-agent and gpg-agent, and then open a new Bash session.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist's Multi-boot USB Drive</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/minimalists-multi-boot-usb-drive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/minimalists-multi-boot-usb-drive/</guid><description>Story Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve realized a fact that I always have needs to keep a multi-boot USB in my pocket for either Linux or Windows installation. There are a lot tools out there already but I don&amp;rsquo;t really like them. At least, I mean, they are too flashy to me. A beautiful boot menu seems not to be attractive. What I need is just a simple and practical maybe a little ugly boot device.</description></item><item><title>Dual-booting Windows VHD and Native Linux on a BIOS+GPT PC</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/dual-booting-windows-vhd-and-native-linux-on-a-bios-gpt-pc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/dual-booting-windows-vhd-and-native-linux-on-a-bios-gpt-pc/</guid><description>Background Previously I wrote a post for this dual-boot scenario. It is a little outdated. In the past year I mostly worked in the Linux environment on my old laptop, so the Windows seems not to be a necessity which occupies a dedicated partition. However, sometimes it is still needed. That is why I started thinking to improve this setup even further. Starting from Windows 7, Windows supports boots from</description></item><item><title>Git中的Subtree和Submodule</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/git%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84subtree%E5%92%8Csubmodule/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/git%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84subtree%E5%92%8Csubmodule/</guid><description>因为最近弄自己的博客，涉及到了版本库嵌套的问题。记下来也算是给自己一个备忘。 为什么有这样的需求 版本库嵌套很好理解，就是在一个 Git 仓库里面包含了</description></item><item><title>Windows+Linux双系统引导手记</title><link>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-linux%E5%8F%8C%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%BC%95%E5%AF%BC%E6%89%8B%E8%AE%B0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 19:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peromage.github.io/p/windows-linux%E5%8F%8C%E7%B3%BB%E7%BB%9F%E5%BC%95%E5%AF%BC%E6%89%8B%E8%AE%B0/</guid><description>0x00 情况简述 由于开发需要 Linux 环境，所以将老的那台笔记本改造成了双系统。 这台电脑的基本情况是这样的，64GB 固态硬盘 + 720GB 机械硬盘（实际可用空间有折</description></item></channel></rss>